Danial Wyn Owen

Address: 7 Ael y Glyn, Harlech, Gwynedd, LL46 2UJ | **Pronouns**: He/Him/They | **Telephone**: 07475909943 | **Email**: danialowen@live.co.uk | **Website**: https://danialowen.netlifv.app/ | **Twitter**: @DanialOwenCDT

Personal Profile

I am a driven person, currently in the final year of my integrated Masters/PhD at the University of Liverpool. Originally a physical geographer, I am currently studying Data Analysis and Society, exploring sensors data in Smart Cities using Python. During my research, I have undertaken an internship, demonstrated, and completed a teaching lectureship position.

Employment History

UNIVERSITY TEACHER IN GEOGRAPHIC DATA SCIENCE | UNIVERSITY OF LIVERPOOL | 09/2021 - 03/2022

- Fixed-term teaching lectureship as module lead for three undergraduate and postgraduate modules in Geographic Data Science.
- Responsible for organizing, communicating, developing, and delivering modules.
- Teaching concepts and the application of Data Science methods using Python on real-world data.
- Piloted a new form of interactive assessment for the students, changed the format of the lectures to increase communication between the students and I, and developed content of existing assignments.
- Academic supervisor for three groups of undergraduate students.

DATA SCIENCE INTERNSHIP | IDOM | 03/2019 - 04/2019

- A data science internship in Sevilla and Madrid with the multinational company, IDOM.
- Responsible for pre-processing, exploring, and visualizing big telecommunication data using Python.
- Successfully pre-processed the data into a suitable, line protocol format to be inputted into visualization platform, Grafana.
- The internship was an excellent experience of working in industry, solo travel and improving my language skills.

DEMONSTRATOR | UNIVERSITY OF LIVERPOOL | 09/2018 - 09/2021

- Demonstrating both undergraduate and master's modules at the Geography and Planning department at the University of Liverpool.
- Supported students with use of QGIS, ArcMap, and R to visualize and analyze the spatial distribution of natural phenomena and human dynamics.

Education

POSTGRADUATE STUDIES | 2018 - PRESENT

Data Analytics and Society Integrated MSc and PhD

UNDERGRADUATE DEGREE | 2015-2018 | UNIVERSITY OF LIVERPOOL

Physical Geography BSc

A LEVELS/AS LEVELS/ADVANCED DIPLOMA | 2013-2015 | COLEG MEIRION DWYFOR, PWLLHELI

• A Level: Mathematics, Geography, Business Studies - BBB

Advanced Diploma: Welsh Baccalaureate
- A*

GCSE | 2008-2013 | YSGOL ARDUDWY, HARLECH

• 9 GCSEs including English, Science, Mathematics - A-A*

Notable Projects

MSC DISSERTATION | TIME-SERIES CLUSTERING OF FOOTFALL DATA | 09/2020

 Applying hierarchical time-series clustering algorithm to classify the change in footfall patterns in Melbourne after the implementation of Covid-19 restrictions over a period of three months using Python.

FIRST PAPER | VECTOR FIELDS TO VISUALISE HUMAN MOBILITY | PRESENT

• Visualizing movement of telecommunication interactions in the city of Milan with vector fields. Employing vector fields to address the well documented issues of visualizing large movement data, reducing visual clutter and occlusion.

Skills & Abilities

COMPUTATIONAL

- Competent working with Python, Jupyter Labs, R, QGIS, ArcGIS.
- SQL course on Udemy using Sequel Server Management Studio (SSMS)
- Microsoft: Word, Excel, Power Point

COMMUNICATION

- Public speaking whilst delivering lectures, presenting at conferences, and being a course representative.
- Fluent in Welsh and English and B1 level Spanish

LICENSE

British Driving License

Referees

PhD Supervisor

Prof. Daniel Arribas-Bel

School of Environmental Sciences,

Roxby Building,

University of Liverpool,

Liverpool.

L69 7ZT.

darribas@liverpool.ac.uk

Recent Employer

Prof. Kathy Burrell,

School of Environmental Sciences,

Roxby Building,

University of Liverpool,

Liverpool,

L69 7ZT.

K.Burrell@liverpool.ac.uk